Liza Cheung

Senior UX Designer at Baozun eCommerce Inc.

capoeirista@yeah.net

Summary

I'm a passionate UX/UI designer. I use user-centered design approaches through my design process.

Specialities: UX/UI Design, Interaction Design, Usability Research, Mobile Web, Mobile Applications, Responsive Web Design, Design Standards Documentation, E-Commerce System, Business Support System, Design Strategy, Front-end Development

Portfolio:

http://lizacheung.me

Experience

Senior UX Designer at Baozun eCommerce Inc.

October 2016 - Present

BZun is a full-service agency that provides design and technology solutions to various brand enterprises. Clients include Nike, GUCCI, Reebok, Converse, Adidas, I.T etc.

UX design lead:

- Conducted quantitative and qualitative user research, created personas.
- Created wireframes, storyboards, user flows to communicate design solutions to various level stakeholders and the development team.
- Interacted with clients to to gain insights into their business.
- Built high-fidelity interactive prototypes and presented them to customers and engineers.
- Conducted usability testings and evaluated feedbacks.
- Iterated rapidly under agile environs, according to product requirements and business requirements.
- Established and maintained design documentations.

Product Designer at Citrix

January 2016 - October 2016 (10 months)

Design lead for recruiting website

- Created information architecture and wireframes based on user needs.
- Brainstorming sessions.
- Communicated design solutions to stakeholders. Collaborated with developers and testers to implement the design.

- Improved the experience of the back-end management system.
- Redesigned virtual meeting desktop app, refreshed UI and enhanced UX.
- Created explorations to solve customer problems and usability issues
- Addressed information overload by optimizing IA and interaction flows
- Created interactive prototypes for usability testing
- Provided design specs to the development team
- Redesigned Citrix face-to-face virtual training tool.
- Delivered and tested design and prototypes for Android, IOS, web and desktop. Worked with PMs and engineers to define the features.
- Recreated Beacon experience based on user feedbacks, optimized interaction flows, aligned UI with Citrix brand identity

Other design tasks:

- Video editing. Design tool: Final Cut Pro, Adobe Creative Suite.
- Graphic design work for office site branding and promotion. Deliverables include: digital ad, posters, brochure, etc.

Freelance UX/UI Designer

October 2015 - January 2016 (4 months)

Design services to various groups/companies/agencies/start-ups.

- Design user interfaces for web, iOS and Android.
- Design wireframes, prototypes and interaction studies.
- Design mobile application user interface.
- Perform user research.
- Improve and update website and mobile application user interface.
- Conduct usability testing.
- Design icons.

Client: China Mobile

- -Consulting service to China Mobile. Lead the redesign of the entertainment Android app for China Mobile called "Migu". Built information architecture, created wireframes, user flows of the app based on user research and product requirements document.
- -Collaborated closely with developers to enhance user experience.

Client: Huawei Technology

- Consulting service to Huawei Technology. Worked on Huawei mobile products. I mainly worked for the Consumer Cloud Service Security and Test Dept. My work required me to collaborate with peers from the Software Engineering UX Design Dept.
- Conducted UX testing and created competitive analysis reports of Huawei native mobile apps.
- Improved UI and interaction experience of Android mobile apps. Released Emotion UI 5.0.

UX/UI Designer, Product (Web&Mobile) Specialist at Focus Technology Co., Ltd.

July 2013 - October 2015 (2 years 4 months)

Mainly worked as a UX/UI designer and user researcher at Focus Tech.

Focus Technology owns various business groups, each has its own products, including enterprise products and consumer products.

Worked on MIC website and mobile app on iOS and Android (made-in-china.com, made-in-china.com for suppliers mobile app, made-in-china.com for buyers mobile app, TYP mobile app):

- Conducted user research with peers from User Research Dept.
- Participated in brainstorming sessions.
- Designed new features that introduced translation tool for the national client mobile platform
- Translated business and product requirements into functional visual designs.
- Built information architecture and created wireframes, user flows. Created both low-fi and hi-fi prototypes. Present design solutions to internal stakeholders.
- Content management and promotion of MIC website. Deliverables include: digital ad, mailing design, etc.
- Iterated in an agile environment.

Worked on internal OA system:

- Designed, evaluated and improved the internal information system used by over 2000 employees at the company.
- Re-architected and redesigned the internal admin interface to be more usable and up-to-date
- Created product requirement documents which helped lead business discussions, drive designs, and guide engineering

Worked on online education mobile app:

- Lead design of the mobile app on iOS.
- Created and managed visual guidelines for the app.
- Conducted interviews with users that powered business and design decisions
- Conducted card sorting, focus groups to collect qualitative information, analyze user tasks.
- Turned user needs into information architecture, wireframes, user flows.
- Communicated design work to internal stakeholders, developers, product managers and designers.

Education

Nanjing Normal University

Bachelor's Degree, Russian&English Bilingual, School of Foreign Languages, Literatures and Linguistics, 2009 - 2014

Activities and Societies: Member of Volunteer Association, Oct 2008 - Jun 2009 Nanjing Hongshan Migrant Children School, volunteer language teacher, Oct 2008 - Jun 2009 Nanjing Normal University Jingwen Library, volunteer librarian, Oct 2008 - Jun 2009 Member of Students' Service Centre, Oct 2009 - Jun 2010 Yunjin Museum, volunteer guide, Apr 2011